{
    "id": "987c1b91594d4fb29e18f1893b3d35ed",
    "title": "Indirect Speech Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He told me that I .................................. very ambitious.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that my father ....................................... me a gift.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "sent",
                "had sent",
                "has sent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "James said that he ...................................... working against heavy odds.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He reminded me that he had often .................................... not to play with fire.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "told",
                "said me",
                "told me"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher remarked that we ....................................... very badly.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did",
                "have done",
                "had done"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "They wrote that it was time we ..................................... the matter.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "settled",
                "have settled",
                "had settled"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The mother said that she .............................................. for her sonâ€™s return.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is longing",
                "was longing",
                "has been longing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He wrote that he was unable to come just then because he .................................. ill.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she ............................................ school long ago.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "left",
                "has left",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I told her that I ........................................... in years.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did not see him",
                "had not seen him",
                "has not seen him"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}